# **Christopher Cooper**

Chris.cooper.ofl@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/chris-cooper88 | 407.259.0025

#### **Profile**

Business Analyst with a track record of delivering B2B solutions for complex issues spanning across cloud-based point of sale, SSRS reporting, and FinTech projects. Through the 5 years of my progressive experience, I have focused on data analysis, gap analysis, and stakeholder interviews to influence and drive product roadmaps. Effective collaboration with business and technical teams to drive out inefficiencies, reduce cost, and increase revenue. If there is a way to get it done, I will quickly identify, and deliver.

#### **CORE PROFICIENCIES**

User Stories
Eliciting Requirements
Gap Analysis
Business Process
Improvements
Agile Methodology
JIRA

Project Management Scrum Conflue

Project ManagementScrumConfluence

### **CERTIFICATIONS, LICENSES, ACOLADES**

Google Foundations: Data, Data, Everywhere

Coursera/Google, Apr 2021

FINRA Anti-Money Laundering (AML)

Al Insights, Oct 2019

**Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO)** 

Braintrust, Apr 2017 - 2019

Going the Extra Mile (GEM)

NBC Sports Group, 2016, 2018, 2019

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### FinTech Business Analyst | NBC Sports Group, Orlando, FL

2019-Present

Payment processor leveraging WorldPay's PayFac network

- Increased payment client adoption by 969 merchants, and processing volume by \$461 MM since 2019 via onboarding automation, KYC refinement, and end-user cloud portal integration
- Leading a team of four to manage, and respond to all processing disputes on behalf of the merchant partners
- Designed systems to identify individuals committing fraud within NBC Sports Group's portfolio of services
- Research & gather requirements for converting eMAF files into C-level reporting
- Self-taught VBA macros to compile ad-hoc reporting for C-level stakeholders when data service resources were not available
- Conduct user interviews and gap analysis to write concise requirements for end user transactional and batch settlement reporting
- Perform quarterly audits of transactional interchange rates to identify where I can cut costs and increase revenue
- · Identify and mitigate ACH rejections

Business Analyst | GolfNow, Orlando, FL

2016-2019

- Lead a data services team as the product expert to improve SSRS reporting from the largest pain-point to the highest rated feature in the point of sale
- Direct product roadmaps by creating and managing feedback campaigns to identify the largest pain points in the cloud-based point of sale
- Consulted the QA division with the objective to refine UAT, and end-to-end regression testing processes to identify bugs and inefficiencies pre-release
- Implement business process improvements for client reported issues to flow through Salesforce and Jira integration
- Design and code a prototype reporting dashboard for the point of sale in Metabase using PostgreSQL

#### Third Party Specialist | GolfNow, Orlando, FL

2015-2016

Point of Sale inventory management and procurement

- Manage on-site and off-site inventory exceeding 8,000 assets by creating an internal asset tagging and tracking system
- Reduce inventory costs by \$50,000 for 2017 through price negotiations with vendors and sourcing alternative products
- Provide detailed reporting for the VP of Finance
- Developed procurement, record keeping, and logistics processes
- Implement an RMA process for in-house and external inventory returns
- Eliminate non-value adding legacy processes inherited through acquisitions

## **EDUCATION | CREDENTIALS**

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, Seminole State College, Orlando, FL